Guide to the Newberry collection of eighteenth, nineteenth, and twentieth century composers, 1830-1930
Department of Special Collections
Newberry collection of eighteenth, nineteenth, and twentieth century composers,
1830-1930
Special Collections M0418
Newberry, Andrew Todd, collector
.5 linear ft.
Stanford University. Libraries. Dept. of Special Collections and University Archives.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
None.
Provenance
Gift of Todd Newberry, 1983.
Container List
- Letters: (Folder 1,)
  - 1. Bülow, Hans Guido von 1830-1834,ALS, 5 May 1879, 1 pg.
  - 2. [Blairdoff?] ALS, [26 May 1900?], 1 pg.
  - 3. Brahms, Johannes 1833-1897,ALS, nd, 2 pp.
  - 4. Daudet, Alphonse 1840-1897,ALS to [Gustave Charpentier 1860-1956].Dealer's description and translation. Nd.
  - 5. Debussy, Claude 1862-1918,ALS to Gabriel Moureg, [1912], 1 pg.
  - 6. Dotzauer, [Justus Johann Friedrich 1783-1860],ALS to Peters, 16 Apr 1830, 2 pp.
  - 7. Dvorák, Antonin 1841-1940,ALS to his publisher, 31 Jan 1883, 4 pp
    with printed transcription. (See #12).
  - 8. [Gerhard?], Benjamin ALS to [Stonllig?], 26 Jun 1884, 2 pp.
  - 9. Kreutzer, Conradin 1780-1849,ALS, 27 Dec [ny], 4 pp.
  - 10. Loti, Pierre 1850-1923,ACS [to Georges Courteline, pseud.], 7 Jan 1917.Dealer's description and translation.
  - 11. Mendelssohn-Bartholdy, Felix 1809-1847,ALS to N. Simrock, 30 Jan 1836, 2 pp.
  - 12. Schulz, Leo ACS to Russell [B. Kingman], 28 Feb [19]30,re Dvorák letter, listed above #7.
  - 13. [Thöne] to Madam, ALS, nd, 1 pg.
    with 1 bar of music.
- Manuscripts and 1 contract: (Folder 2,)
  - 14. Cimarosa, Domenico 1749-1801,music ms Orazi e i Curiazi, copied for [Clara Rosalio?] by Domenico Dragonetti, nd, 17 pp.
  - 15. Franchomme, Auguste 1808-1884,music ms Fantasie pour le violincello.., 1832, 6 pp.
    Bookplate of Henry Cummings.
  - 16. Kreutzer, Conradin 1780-1849,music ms Riga, 27 Aug 1849, 3½ pp.
  - 17. Piatti, Alfredo 1822-1901,music ms Ave Maria, 7 Feb 1884, 2 pp.
  - 18. Servais, Adrien-Francois 1807-1866,music ms Larghetto, nd, 2 pp.
  - 19. Topper, David, music ms Violincello solo, opus 24, nd, 1 pg.
  - 20. Dragonetti, Domenico 1763-1846,contract with the King's Theatre, 14 Jan 1824, 4 pp
    with printed obituary [1846].
- Printed material: (Folder 3,)
  - 21. Dragonetti, Domenico 1763-1846,engraving of, from newspaper, [1846].
  - 22. Martinet, hand-colored engraving Guepier.., [18th century],plate 649.
  - 23. Mendelssohn-Bartholdy, Felix 1809-1847,engraving of, nd.
  - 24. Mendelssohn-Bartholdy, Felix, engraving of by J. Blechinger.
  - 25. Mendelssohn-Bartholdy, Felix, engraving of by A.H. Payne & W.C. Wrankmore.
  - 26. Paganini, Nicolo 1782-1840,facsimile ACS, 19 Oct 1833.
  - 27. Wieniawski, Heinrich 1835-1880,one portrait engraving of, nd,5 newsclippings including obituaries.